

Tuomo Kareoja

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

Derfflingerstraße 22a 2-19, 10785 Berlin, Germany

🛮 (+49) 015 906817714 | 💌 tuomo.kareoja@gmail.com | 🖸 TuomoKareoja | 🖹 tuomo-kareoja | 🛅 tuomo-kareoja

Summary and Skills _____

Data scientist/engineer specialized in relational databases, data pipelines and interactive dashboards. Experience in discrete-event simulations, customer lifetime value/segmentation modelling, and using explorative modelling of business outcomes. Domain knowledge in micro-mobility, healthcare, customer analysis, finance and national elections.

Programming Python, R, bash, LaTeX

BI Tools Microsoft Power BI, Tableau, Looker

Databases DBT, Snowflake, Redshift, Posgresql, Microsoft SQL Server

DevOps Docker, DataDog, PagerDuty, CircleCl

Languages Finnish (native), English (fluent), German and Swedish (basic)

EU citizen

Experience _____

Senior Data Scientist

Berlin, Germany

TIER MOBILITY Jan. 2021 - Present

• Acquisition, CRM and pricing analytics (Python, Snowflake, DBT, Looker)

· Understanding customers with segmentation and customer lifetime value modelling (CatBoost, RFM models, Airflow)

• Interim head of commercial analytics from 2020 December to beginning of March 2021

Data Scientist Berlin, Germany

TIER MOBILITY Feb. 2020 - Dec. 2020

• Data ingestion, operational analytics and geographic visualizations (Python, ETLeap, AWS, Redshift, DBT, Looker)

Data Scientist Helsinki, Finland

Nordic Healthcare Group Feb. 2019 - Feb 2020

Integrating medical data from multiple hospitals to one database for hospital benchmarking (PostgreSQL, Python)

· Champion for version control, project management tools, reproducibility and internal documentation (GitLab, Asana, ClickUp, Docker, Conda)

Data Analyst Helsinki, Finland

Nordic Healthcare Group

Jan. 2017 - Feb. 2019

- · Data processing and interactive visualization for hospital benchmarking in internal medicine and emergency care (Power BI, R, Python, PostgreSQL)
- Discrete-event simulations of hospital processes (Python, SimPy, Plotly, Dash)

Junior Data Analyst Helsinki, Finland

Grey-Hen Oy Sep. 2016 - Dec. 2016

- Quality control of the automated data gathering and report generation for models predicting prizes of used cars (SAS, R, Microsoft SQL Server)
- Documentation of the data pipelines and datasets

Teaching Assistant Helsinki, Finland

University of Helsinki Jan. 2012 - Dec. 2016

• TA in numerous statistical courses at the departments of social psychology and statistics (SPSS, R)

Medical Typist (Part-Time)

Helsinki, Finland

HUS Service Jul. 2014 - Aug. 2015

· Typing doctors' dictations and turning them into medical records and other documents, booking medical procedures

Trainee (Internship) Helsinki, Finland

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF HEALTH AND WELFARE (THL)

Jun. 2013 - Sep. 2013

• Trainee in the unit "Advancing Mental Health" and the unit "Mental Health Problems and Substance Abuse Services". My duties were analyzing survey results of the mental health situation in Lapland and testing the reliability of psychological measurements in patients with psychosis. Work was done using statistical programs SPSS and R

Hospital Service Technician

Helsinki, Finland

PALMIA, CITY OF HELSINKI

Jun. 2009 - Jul. 2009

· Managing mortuary, providing oxygen bottles to wards and transporting patients from the wards to treatments and back

Education

Data Science Bootcamp Berlin, Germany

Uві**Q**UM

Jul. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- On-site fulltime 5 month project based training course
- Technologies used: Python, R, MySQL, Spark, AWS, Docker
- Algorithms used: GLM, KNN, RF, SVM, GBM, apriori, SARIMAX, Prophet...

B.A. in Statistics Helsinki, Finland

University of Helsinki

- Weighted grade average: 4.53 (scale 0-5)
- · Bachelor thesis was about applying hierarchical Bayesian models to combine multiple n-of-1 clinical trials

M.A. in Social Psychology Helsinki, Finland UNIVERSITY OF HELSINKI 2012 - 2015

• Weighted grade average: 4.91 (scale 0-5), Master's thesis: Eximia

· Master thesis was an experimental study comparing the effect of two types of meditation practices with over 1000 participants

B.A. in Social Psychology Helsinki, Finland

University of Helsinki 2010 - 2012

• Weighted grade average: 4.02 (scale 0-5)